父亲的诅咒 第六年 第七年 第八年
政府通缉 杰克·斯派洛 活要见人死要见尸
飞行的荷兰人号
悬赏 杰克·斯派洛
圣马丁岛 加勒比海
狗与女人 不得入内
悬赏通缉 杰克·斯派洛 臭名昭著的海盗
死鸥号
别乱动 混蛋
船长 拜托 我再也不想当船长了
Sparrow 也有麻雀的意思
Horologist 与 Whore妓女读法相似
刽子手湾 闲人莫入
加勒比海盗5：死无对证
- 父亲 - 亨利 你都做了什么
- Father. - Henry. What have you done?
- 我说了会找到你 - 看看我 儿子
- I said I'd find you. - Look at me, son.
- 我不在乎 - 荷兰人号上没有你的位置
- I don't care! - There is no place for you on the Dutchman.
他们知道你来了 回家去找你妈妈
They know you're here... Get home to your mother.
不
No!
- 趁着来得及 快跑 - 我不走
- Leave now, before it's too late. - I won't!
我决不放弃 要是你抛弃我
I'll never stop... And if you throw me over,
我马上就回来
I'll come straight back...
你还不明白 我被诅咒困在这艘船上了
Don't you see, I'm cursed to this ship?
这就是我来的原因
That's why I'm here.
我应该知道如何打破诅咒
I think I know a way to break your curse.
让你解脱荷兰人号的束缚
To free you from the Dutchman.
- 亨利 不行 - 我读到过一个宝物
- Henry, no. - I've read about a treasure.
蕴藏了大海全部力量的宝物
A treasure that holds all the power of the sea,
波塞冬的三叉戟
The Trident of Poseidon,
能打破诅咒
can break your curse.
亨利
Henry.
三叉戟的下落无人知晓
The Trident can never be found.
我连你都能找到
I found you.
- 那只是个传说 - 就像你和
- It's just a tale. - Like the tales of you
杰克·斯派洛船长的传说吗
And Captain Jack Sparrow?
他会帮我找到三叉戟
He will help me find the trident.
你离杰克远点
You stay away from Jack.
永远远离大海 你要停止假装自己是个
Leave the sea forever. You've to stop acting like a.
- 海盗 - 我决不放弃
- A pirate. - I won't stop.
我想要你回家
I want you to come home.
亨利
Henry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我的诅咒永远无法被打破
My curse will never be broken.
这是我的命运
This is my fate.
别再来找我了
You must let me go.
我爱你儿子
I love you son.
杰克·斯派洛船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
九年后
你们这帮卑贱的苦力给我快点 抽水
Faster you pathetic built rats, you pump the builds...
排到排水管
And fill the scuppers.
我们要去追赶海盗
We are chasing down pirates.
亨利你给我回来 除非你想再被赶下去
Henry get back here. You don't wanna get kicked off an another ship.
那是艘荷兰三桅帆船 可能是海盗博尼特偷来的
It's a Dutch bark. Probably stolen by the Pirate Bonet.
天啊
My God.
我警告过你不要擅离职守 小子
I warned you of leaving your post, boy.
我要找船长
I need to speak with the captain.
- 你说什么 - 走开
- What did you say? - Move.
即将迎战 长官
It is going in, sir.
追到她
Chase her down.
不 别去
No, don't do it!
别那么做
Don't do it...
小子 轮不到你来命令船长
You will not address a Captain, boy.
长官 请看看地图 恐怕你是要带我们
Sir, look at your charts. I believe you're sailing us,
驶向魔鬼三角洲了
in to the Devil's Triangle.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear this man?
这位见习水手居然相信老水手编的传说
This landsman, believes an old sailor's myth.
长官
Sir.
恕我直言 我一生都在研究
With all due respect I have spent my life studying,
大海的传说 我了解每个故事与诅咒
the myths of the sea. I know every legend and every curse.
我知道 开进三角洲的船只
Do I know, ships that sail into the triangle
不一定都能成功返回
do not necessarily sail out.
请别担心 长官
Don't worry sir.
- 显然这小子脑子进水了 - 长官 请相信我的话
- This one is clearly disturbed. - Sir, trust in what I say.
改变航向
Change your course.
你竟敢命令我 小毛孩
You dare to give me orders, boy?
抓住他
Arrest him!
特纳
Turner!
我不会让大家因你丧命的
I'll not let you kill us all.
回来
Come on.
你这是叛国
This is treason!
把他关起来
Lock him up.
- 不要 - 准备交战
- No. - We're going in.
特纳 这是你最后的机会了
This was your last chance, Turner.
要是我管事 我会把你吊死在横桅上
If it were up to me, I would string you from the yard arm.
下一个
On deck!
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
他已经死了
He's dead.
被埋在圣马丁岛上的无标记墓地中
Buried in an unmarked graveyard of St. Martin.
长官 水里有东西
Sir, there's something in the water.
右舷有船出现
Ship to starboard!
那不是船 是残骸
That's no ship, sir. It's a shipwreck.
不
No.
她正直直向我们驶来
She's sailing straight towards us.
开火
Open fire!
你是什么鬼东西
What are you?
死亡
Death.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
你认识这位海盗吗
Do you know this pirate?
- 只听过名字 - 你能帮我找到他吗
- Only by name. - You could look me for him?
- 你同意了是吗 - 是的
- Is that a yes? - Yes.
三角洲诅咒了我们太多年
For too many years the Triangle has cursed us.
让我们困在这活地狱里
Condemned us to this Hell on Earth.
我们逃离的关键
The key to our escape...
是杰克·斯派洛与他手中的罗盘
Is Jack Sparrow and the compass, which he holds.
别 别害怕我 孩子
No, no. No need to fear me boy.
我总会留一个活人
I always leave one man alive.
将我的故事流传
To tell the tale.
帮我找到斯派洛传话给他
Find Sparrow for me and relay a message.
就说是萨拉查船长说的
From Capitan Salazar.
萨拉查
Salazar.
告诉他我会重见天日
Tell him I'll behold the daylight again.
等到那天
And on that day.
死亡
Death.
死亡 会找上他的门
Death... comes straight for him.
可以请你帮我传话吗
Would you say that to him? Please?
- 当然 - 我也希望自己告诉他 但是
- Yes. - I wish I could tell him myself, but.
死人是不会告密的
Dead men tell no tales.
卡丽娜·史密斯
Carina Smyth.
你是恶魔诞下的孤儿
You're an orphan, born of the devil.
你被告施巫术
Accused of practicing witchcraft.
死之前
Before you die.
有什么想忏悔的吗
Do you have anything to confess?
我忏悔我不是女巫 我只是个懂科学的女人
I confess that I am not a witch. That I'm a woman of science.
我忏悔我靠自己活着 我只有一家奶牛场
I confess that I have survived on my own, with nothing but a dairy
是从我未曾谋面未曾谋面的父亲那继承的
From a father I never knew.
我只是在探寻自己的身世
On a quest for the truth of who I am.
我忏悔在放弃探寻之前我绝不让自己死
I confess that I will die before I give up this search.
我忏悔
And I confess.
在我们说话间 我已经撬了锁
That while we've been talking. I pitched this lock.
今日我们庆祝圣马丁岛的皇家银行的落成
Today we dedicate The Royal Bank of St. Martin.
加勒比海域最安全的银行机构
The most secure banking institution in the Caribbean.
我们新的金库
Our new vault...
有5英尺厚
Is 5 inches thick.
一英吨重
And weighs an imperial ton.
看到她了
I've got her!
抓住她
Get her!
别让她跑了
Don't let her get away.
拦下女巫
Stop that witch!
有了这家银行 圣马丁镇
With this bank, the town of St. Martin,
也步入了现代世界
enters the modern world.
- 很抱歉 长官 - 那女巫挣脱了枷锁
- I'm so sorry, sir. - The witch's escaped the chains.
找到那个坏女人
Find that wicked lass.
否则找你替代
Or you swing in her place.
- 告辞 - 告辞
- Sir. - Sir.
没有任何人 或者军队
No man... Nor army.
能从圣马丁抢走一块金子
Can ever rob the gold from St. Martin.
打开金库
Open the vault!
海盗
Pirate!
Pirate.?
海盗
Pirates!
这问题也许很奇怪 能有人给我解释一下
This may seem a peculiar question. Could someone explain to me...
为什么我在这吗
To why I'm here?
多久
How long?
不 等一下 我想起来了
No, no no, wait, it's coming to me.
让我整理下思绪
Need just a moment to clear mi head.
准备进攻
Make ready!
先别开火 金库里还有个女人
Hold your fire. There's a woman with him in the vault.
长官 恐怕 那是你老婆
Sir, I believe... that's your wife.
弗朗西斯
Francis?
想起来了
Oh, I've got it!
想起来了 我要抢银行
I've got it. I'm robbing the bank!
朝他开枪
Shoot him!
这可不在计划之中
That was not part of the plan.
拦下他 别让他跑了
Stop him! Don't let him get away!
从没有女人会用我的望远镜
No woman has ever handled my Herschel
开路
Clear the path.
不 不要啊
No, no, no, no!
停下 快停下
Stop, stop... stop!
右急转
Hard to starboard!
先生 你的天轴歪了
Sir, your celestial fix was off.
我为你向北调整了两度 你的地图不会再不准确了
I have adjusted two degrees north. Your map will no longer be imprecise.
不过你得重新画了
Although you will have to start again with it.
你是女巫
You're a witch.
我不是 因为记录了两百多颗星星
No, I'm not. Am I a witch for having cataloged.
- 我就成了女巫吗 - 女巫
- Over 200 stars? - Witch!
血月要来临了
There is a blood moon coming.
我只是想来买东西
I simply need to purchase.
精密记时表
A chronometer.
我愿意出双倍价钱让你卖给我这个女人
I pay you double for selling to a woman.
来人啊
Help me!
快来人 我店里有个女巫
Help! Help! There is a witch in my shop.
还有个海盗
And a pirate!
我店里有个海盗和女巫
There is a witch and a pirate in my shop.
那你今天可真幸运
Well this is your lucky day!
你们有谁看到我的银行了吗
Have either of the four of you seen my bank?
找到了
Found it.
- 原计划里有你吗 - 我不想惹麻烦
- Were you part of the plan? - I am not looking for trouble.
你活着真没意思
What a horrible way to live.
- 别让那女巫跑了 抓住她 - 我们被困住了
- Stop that Witch! Get her! - We're trapped.
该怎么办
What do we do?
你得尖叫一下
You need to scream.
在那 抓住那女人
Over there! Secure that woman!
- 你个卑鄙的海盗 - 没必要指名道谢
- You filthy pirate! - No need for lame calling!
杰克
Jack!
桥
Bridge?
是空的
It's empty!
钱去哪了
Where is the dash?
你们觉得抢银行很容易吗
Do you think that robbing a bank is easy?
现在一个子儿都没抢到
You gaggle of gutless use of the wound...
还不是被你们这群饭桶害的
Guilty of putting me on this dreadful pickle in the first place.
都排好队 按老规矩上交保护费
Now line up... And offer me a tribute.
你还要我们给你钱
Do you want us to pay you?
我是不是这艘船的船长
Am I not the captain of this ship?
你把这叫船
You call this a ship?
- 说好的财宝呢 - 我们全都快饿死了
- Where is the treasure? - All of us are starving.
我们不会再跟着一个连船都没有的船长
We'll no longer follow a captain without a ship.
我有一艘船
I have a ship.
黑珍珠号从未离开我身边
Black Pearl has never left me side.
现在海盗巴巴罗萨才是海上的霸主
The pirate Barbarossa rules these seas now.
他有10艘船 全副武装
Has 10 ships. Guns full.
更别提他的炮弹了 听说每颗炮弹有18磅重
Not to mention his canon balls. Eighteen pounds each they say.
瘸子的球有那么重
One legged man with 18 pound balls?
难怪他走起路来那么好笑
That's why he walks funny.
好了 伙计们
Oh come, come mates?
我们不是一起找到了马其顿的宝藏吗
Did we not find the treasure of Macedonia together?
那就是堆烂木头
It was a troll of rotten wood.
- 迈达斯国王的金子 - 那是堆驴粪
- Gold of King Midas. - A pile of donkey dung.
认命吧 杰克 你就是个倒霉鬼
Face it Jack. Bad luck dogs you,
流年不利
day & night.
这都是些无稽之谈
Now that is a bliss of fabrication.
- 你丢了你的好运 - 你也丢了你的船
- You've lost your luck. - You've lost your ship.
现在 你还丢了你的船员
Now... you've lost your crew.
杰克·斯派洛已经不是我们的船长了
Jack Sparrow is no longer our captain.
对不起杰克 跟着你实在混不下去了
I'm sorry Jack. But we've reached the end of the horizon.
你们全被解雇了
You're all dismissed.
全部 解雇了
All of ya! Dismissed!
以后别想再和杰克·斯派洛船长一起出海了
Never sail with Captain Jack Sparrow again.
知道吗
Tell you that.
全镇的人都在讨论你
The whole town speaks of you.
君王号上唯一的幸存者
The only survivor of the Monarch. A boy who pelled...
一个靠着块木头 逆流而上
All the way to St Martin, against the tide.
一路划到了圣马丁的男孩
On a piece of wood.
嘴里口齿不清得念叨海盗
Now gibbering about pirates.
和三叉戟
And tridents.
拜托长官 帮我拿掉镣铐吧
Please sir, let me go off these chains.
我的职责是保护这个岛以及这片海域
My job is to protect this island and these waters.
而你的袖子被撕掉了 这是叛徒的标志
And your sleeves have been ripped, The mark of treason.
我们被死人袭击了
We were attacked by the dead.
那你就是临阵逃脱了
You're a coward who ran from battle.
按逃兵处死
That is how you die.
- 我不相信你是个逃兵 - 请让我一个人静静
- I don't believe you're a coward. - Please leave me sister.
我冒着生命危险到这来
I've risked my life to come here.
来瞧瞧传言是不是真的
To see if the rumors are true.
- 你是在说三叉戟吗 - 你是谁
- Are you speak of the Trident? - Who are you?
- 告诉我你为什么要找三叉戟 - 三叉戟可以
- Tell me why you seek the trident? - The Trident can break,
破除海上的任何诅咒
any curse at sea.
我父亲就陷入了类似的诅咒
My father is trapped by such a curse.
你知道诅咒这种事并没有科学依据
You're aware that curses are not supported by science.
- 科学也不承认鬼魂存在 - 看来你真的疯了
- Neither the ghosts. - So you have gone mad?
- 我就不该到这来 - 那你为什么要来这
- I should never have come here. - Then why did you come here?
因为我要离开这岛
Because I need to get off this island.
解读无人能懂的海图
To solve the map.
无人能懂的海图
"No man can read".
波塞冬留下的海图
Left by Poseidon himself.
- 你知道那个传说 - 我看过所有的译本
- You've read the ancient text? - In each language they were written.
但没人见过那海图
But this map has never been seen or read,
没人看得懂
by any man.
幸好我是个女人
Luckily I am a woman.
这是伽利略·伽利莱的日记
This is the diary of Galileo Galilei.
他用尽一生在寻找三叉戟
He's spent his life searching for the Trident,
他为了找三叉戟发明了望远镜
It's why he invented the spyglass.
所以天文学家才总是盯着天空看
Why astronomers' spend their lives staring in to the sky.
你是说没人能读懂的海图
So you're saying the map no man can read,
就藏在星空里
Is hidden in the stars?
这是我父亲留给我的 他相信我能找到
It was left to me by my father. He believe I could find...
别人找不到的东西
What no man has ever found.
我不会让他失望的
I will not let him down.
很快就会出现血月
Soon, there will be blood moon.
只有那时我才能解读海图
Only then can the map be read.
- 才能找到三叉戟 - 你是谁
- And the Trident found. - Who are you?
- 卡丽娜·史密斯 - 如果你想救你父亲
- Carina Smyth! - If you have to save your father,
你就得先救我 找艘船
you'll have to save me. Find us a ship.
我们会找到三叉戟的
And the Trident will be ours.
给我回来 女巫
Come to me Witch!
他跑了
He's gone!
他跑了 长官
He's gone sir.
找到那个逃兵
Find that coward!
把他和那女巫一起吊死
He will hang with the witch.
觉得杰克船长老了不中用了
Think Capt. Jack washed up right?
我有好几年没洗澡了
I have not had a wash in years.
搜查那条巷子
Check the alley down there.
你们两个去搜教堂 剩下的跟我来
You two, check the church. Rest of you, with me.
糟了
Bugger!
- 能赏口酒喝吗 - 先把钱拿出来
- May I please have a drink, please? - Show me your silver.
要钱
Silver?
做个交易怎样
How about a trade?
给我一瓶酒
Give me the bottle.
船长
Capitan.
怎么了
What's happening?
杰克·斯派洛 杰克·斯派洛刚刚把他的罗盘送人了
Jack Sparrow, Jack Sparrow has given away the compass.
阳光
Daylight!
我们自由了
We're free!
好极 好极 是时候去狩猎那个海盗了
Now, now, it's time, to hunt a pirate.
海盗的人生啊
Pirate's life.
来吧 宝贝
Come to Daddy.
那家伙就是我们要找的人
Just the man we've been looking for.
为什么 找我干嘛
Why? Why am I looked for?
全城公告 杰克·斯派洛
Let it be known that the pirate Jack Sparrow...
将在天亮被处决
Will be executed at dawn.
处决
Executed?
我不会再来这镇子了 长官 我说到做到
I will never set foot in this town again, sir. Be mark of words.
释放海洋的力量
To release the power of the sea.
即可分离一切
One must divide.
是个岛 星星指引向一座岛
It's an island. The stars lead to an island.
- 我在找一个海盗 杰克·斯派洛 - 滚开
- I'm looking for a pirate, Jack Sparrow. - Bugger off!
我跟你打听个人
I need to speak with you.
- 把你的剑给我 - 我没有剑
- Give me your sword. - I don't have a sword.
- 什么样的士兵没有武器 - 我因为叛国被通缉
- What kind of soldier has no weapon? - I'm counting on to the treason.
看来你也不是个好兵
So, not a very good kind.
我在找杰克·斯派洛船长
I am looking for a pirate, Captain Jack Sparrow?
今天是你的幸运日 因为正巧我就是
Today is your lucky day. Because I just happen to be...
船长 杰克·斯派洛
Captain Jack Sparrow.
不 不会吧
No, it can't be.
我找了那么多年的人 竟是这样
I've spent years searching for... this?
伟大的杰克·斯派洛怎么会是个坐牢的酒鬼
The great Jack Sparrow is not some drunk in a cell.
你的船呢 船员呢
Do you even have a ship? A crew?
裤子呢
Pants.
伟大的海盗不拘小节
A great pirate does not require such intricacies.
你知道我等这一刻等了多久吗
Do you know how long I've been waiting for this moment?
我冒了多少险才到了这
The risks I've taken to be here?
- 你确定你就是杰克·斯派洛 - 最该问的是
- Are you sure you're the Jack Sparrow? - The real question is...
- 你是谁 - 我叫亨利·特纳
- Who are you? - My name is Henry Turner.
威尔·特纳和伊丽莎白·斯旺的儿子
Son of Will Turner and Elisabeth Swann.
你是他俩生的坏小子
You are the evil spawn of them two?
你妈有和你提到过我吗
Does mommy ever ask about me?
没有
No.
说说嘛 她梦里一直呼唤我的名字吧
Go on. She calls my name in the sleep?
她从没提起过你
She never spoke of you.
你确定我们说的是同一个人？
Are you sure we're talking about the same people?
男是个被诅咒的太监
He is a cursed eunuch.
女的有一头金发 很固执
She has golden hair, stubborn,
撅着嘴 脖子像长颈鹿一样
pouty lips. Neck like a giraffe.
- 还有一对傲人的 - 是 是 就是她
- And two of the those wonderful. - Yes Yes, it's her!
听着 杰克
I need you to listen Jack.
我现在只能指望你了
Because at the moment you're all I have got.
我找到了救我父亲的方法 有一件神器能打破诅咒
I found the way to save my father. There is one thing that can break his curse.
让他离开荷兰人号
And free him from the Dutchmen.
波塞冬的三叉戟
The Trident of Poseidon.
要找这件宝物
The treasure that can be found with...
就得靠一张没人看得懂的海图
the map that no man can read.
从没听说过
Never heard of it.
杰克 这里关着个女孩
There's a girl inside this prison Jack,
她有那张海图
who holds that map.
血月已经开始了 三叉戟就要现世
The moon has turned to blood, the trident will be found.
你将成为掌控大海的人
And you could be the one who holds the sea.
有了它你就能重振雄风
And with it become all that you once were.
伟大的
The great.
杰克
Jack!
对不起 你还在说吗
Oh, I'm so sorry. Were you still talking?
还有件事
One more thing.
一个你认识的人留了一条消息 他叫萨拉查船长
A message from someone you know, named Captain Salazar.
我曾经认识一个西班牙人叫这个名字
I once knew a Spaniard named.
是西班牙语
Something in Spanish.
海上屠夫
El Matador Del Mar. The butcher of the sea.
他 不不不 他死了 这点我很开心
Him? No, no, no. Quite happily he's dead.
死的很透很透 他的船沉了
Very, very dead. Ship went down...
沉在了魔鬼三角洲里
Inside the triangle.
他来找你了 杰克 来报仇了
He's coming for you Jack, to seek revenge.
死人的传说就是这样讲的
As the dead man's tale is told...
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
他怎么说
What did he say?
他说你的罗盘是
He said your compass was the key
他逃脱的关键 一支死人的大军
to his escape. An army of dead,
直接朝着你来了 杰克
are coming straight for you, Jack.
海神三叉戟是你的唯一的希望
The Trident of Poseidon is your only hope.
我们说定了吗
Do we have an accord?
- 我才不要去那里告诉他 - 是你的主意
- I am not going in there to tell him. - It was your idea!
不 我的主意是让你去告诉他
No, it was my idea for you to tell him.
他更喜欢你
He likes you more than me.
他不喜欢任何人
He doesn't like anybody.
抱歉 先生 我们知道您说过永远不要打扰您
Sorry sir. We know you said never to disturb you.
或者没有好的理由就跑过来
Or to come in without good cause.
或者开口说话前没有先
Or to speak without first.
请教您我们的想法
To ask you now whether our,
是不是绝对必要
thoughts were absolutely necessary.
好比那一次我们的船着火了
Like the time the ship was on fire.
那是一个必要的想法的例子
That being an example of necessary thought.
所以 我们再次为引发那场火道歉
So again, we do apologize for starting that fire.
讲
Speak!
是我们的船 先生 它们正在遭受敌人的攻击
It's the ships, sir. They are being attacked by an enemy...
- 敌人抢走了财宝 - 他们随随便便就会杀人
- That takes the Riches. - Kills without provocation.
我的船 不可能
My ships? Not possible!
其中的三艘已经沉了 先生
Three of them already been sunk, Sir.
下手的是一个叫萨拉曼达的船长
They have been sunk by a captain called Salamander!
萨拉查
Salazar.
Salazar!
就是他 先生大人 他在每一艘船上留下一个活口
That's him, your sireness! He leaves one man from each vessel...
来讲他的故事 整个舰队都在沉没
To tell the tale. The entire fleet is being sunk.
我们马上就要死了
And we'll soon be dead.
而且很有可能关门大吉
And quite possibly out of business.
我需要和你们的女巫待一段时间
I'll be needing some time with your witch...
我一直在等你 船长 你要喝杯茶吗
I have been expecting you Captain. Perhaps you would like some tea.
不用了 非常感谢
I shall pass, thank you kindly.
进我的门的代价是鲜血 船长
The price of crossing my door is blood, Captain.
这就解释了为什么你生意这么冷清
That explains why you're not so busy.
每个人最终都会付出代价的
Everyone pays, eventually.
沙萨 你我很久以前就有交情了
Shansa, you and I made a bond long ago.
我把你从绞刑架上救了下来
I saved you from the gallows.
记得吗
Remember?
而我也诅咒了你的敌人
And I cursed your enemies.
现在你心怀恐惧来找我
But now you come to me with fear.
在死人统治了大海的时候
As the dead have taken command over the sea.
死人找我做什么
And what would the dead be wanting with me?
不是你 船长
Not you, Captain.
- 他们在找斯派洛 - 杰克？
- They're searching for a Sparrow. - Jack?
杰克会乘船去找三叉戟 带着一个女孩和一颗珍珠
Jack who sails for the trident... With a girl and a Pearl.
三叉戟永远不能被找到
The trident can never be found.
三叉戟是杰克唯一的希望
The trident is Jack's only hope.
死者统治了大海
The dead are conquering the sea,
却无法登上陆地
unable to step on dry land.
也许你该退休 回到乡下生活了
Maybe you should retire to the country side.
你说回到草地吗
You mean grass?
在农场里
On a farm?
给牛挤奶 制作奶酪
Milking a cow, making cheese.
- 看着他们把我的财宝都沉掉 - 船长 请你自己想想
- While they sink mi treasure? - Ask yourself this, Captain.
- 这些财宝值得你去死吗 - 我是一个海盗
- Is this treasure worth dying for? - I'm a pirate.
永远都是 所以我该怎么保护
Always will be! So how do I save,
- 属于我的东西 - 杰克有一个罗盘
- what be mine. - Jack held a compass.
会指给你你最渴望的东西
Which points you to the thing you desire most.
但是你如果背叛罗盘
But betray the compass...
它就会释放你最大的恐惧
And it releases your greatest fear.
而一个海盗最大的恐惧是萨拉查 是吧
And a pirate's greatest fear will be Salazar, is it?
- 你怎么拿到这个的 - 我自有办法
- How did you get this? - I have my ways.
把他们带向杰克 在他找到三叉戟之前
Lead them to Jack before he finds the trident.
这样你的财宝都会回到你的手中
And all your treasure will come back to you.
是时候和死者做一笔交易了
Time to make a deal with the dead.
快点 海盗
Come on, pirate.
等一下 停
Hold on, stop.
- 杰克叔叔 - 小杰 你怎么样
- Uncle Jack! - Jackie boy, how is it going?
没什么可抱怨的 你呢
Can't complain really. You?
我在这里等了一上午了 等着被打一顿
I've been waiting all morning in here, for a beating.
- 但是这里的服务太差了 - 太不像话了
- But the service is terrible. - Shameful.
杰克
Jack.
海洋将被鲜血染红
The oceans have turned to blood.
你最好待在陆地上 那里比较安全
Best to stay on dry land, where it's safe.
我就要在陆地上被处死了
I'm about to be executed on dry land.
有道理
Good point.
我给你讲过骷髅的故事吗
Did I ever told you about the skeleton?
你讲过 讲过好多次了
Yes you have, many times.
骷髅走进一个酒馆 点了一杯酒
Skeleton goes into a bar, orders a beer.
还要了一个拖把
And a mop.
一如既往地好笑
Funny as ever.
好了 走吧
Come on let's go!
如果他们要开你的膛 记得找维克托 他手法最好
If they disembowel you, ask for Viktor. He's got the softest hands.
谢了！
Thank you!
提我的名字 他们就不会砍掉你的脚
And mention my name, they won't cut your feet off.
来吧 你是第一个
Come on. You're first!
海盗 你想怎么死
And how would you like to die pirate?
绞死 枪决 还有一个新的发明
Hanging, firing squad or a new invention.
- 断头台 - 断头台
- The guillotine. - Guillotine?
听起来像法国的东西 我喜欢法国的东西
Sounds french. I love the French.
你知道他们发明了蛋黄酱吗
Did you know they've invented mayonnaise?
能有多差劲 是法国的 对吧
How bad could it be? It's French, right?
哦 我的锅 我改变主意啦
Oh, my bad! I change mi mind...
请可怜可怜我 我睡觉都尿床的
No please have mercy for me. I am a bed wetter.
不是吧
Oh, come on!
我为这事还要爬楼梯吗
I mean I have to walk upstairs as well for this?
- 把篮子拿过来 - 篮子 干什么用的
- Bring the basket. - Basket... why?
把他摁倒
Step him down!
我有个主意
Here's an idea.
要不我们试试传统的石刑吧 我现在很希望被石刑处死
Why don't we try good old fashioned stoning? I'd kill to be stoned right now.
能让人群都参与进来 不是吗
Gets the crowd involved, doesn't it?
我希望就开膛一事同维克托谈谈
I should like to speak to Victor in disembowelment.
我希望同维克谈谈
I should like to speak to Vic.
我一般很少抱怨
I'm not the one who, complain normally,
但是这个篮子里都是脑袋
but this basket is full of heads.
卡丽娜·史密斯的遗言 安静
Final words of Carina Smyth. quiet!
卡丽娜·史密斯的遗言
The final words of Carina Smyth.
她说 我不是个女巫
It says. I'm not a witch.
但是我原谅了你们这常见的愚蠢的无知和低能的大脑
But I forgive your common dim witlessness and feeble brains.
简单来说 你们大部分人都有个羊脑子
In short, most of you have the mind of a goat.
请原谅 长官 对于那些将要被处死之人
Pardon me sir. It's not common practice...
这不是常见的做法吧
for those about to be executed.
让他们留下遗言 或者说 类似的
To be granted a last, I don't know, some of a...?
我正在说话 麻烦你耐心一点
I believe I was making a point. If you could just be patient.
不
No.
我脑袋就要被砍掉了 我这里很急
My head's about to be lopped off. Hence the urgency.
我脖子还要断掉了呢
And my neck is to be broken.
你是否知道在个别情况下 脖子并不真的会断掉
Did you know that on occasion, the neck doesn't actually break.
- 只是会很疼 - 什么
- It just hurts. - What?
是的
Oh Yes.
我见过有的人挂了好几个小时
I have seen men swing for hours.
眼珠凸出 舌头膨胀
Eyes bulging, tongues swelling.
- 发出恶心的咯咯声 - 能让我说完吗
- Revolting gurgling sound. - May I finish?
不能 你太幸运了
No. You're lucky.
我还想被绞死呢
Wish I was hung.
- 先杀了这个破海盗 我等着 - 女巫优先！
- Kill the filthy pirate, I'll wait... - The witch is first!
我不是女巫 你有没有在听啊
I'm not a witch. Did not you listen?
有个羊脑子很难认真听的
Quite hard to listen when you have the mind of a goat.
够了 两个人都杀了
Enough! Kill them both.
好
Yes!
想多了吧 你以为你能打败我们
Guess another news. Did you think you could defeat us boy?
不 先生 我只是转移注意力的
No sir, I'm just a diversion.
开火
Fire!
我还是想被石刑
I still rather be stoned.
装弹
Reload!
谢了
Thank you.
过来 你个海盗渣滓
Come here. You Pirate Scum!
嘿
Hey!
你干什么 不不不不
What do you do? No, no, no, no!
马
Horses?
- 谢谢你 - 不客气 小姐
- Thank you. - You're welcome Mi lady.
接住你了
Got you!
你来接谁来了 叛徒
Who you'd come tolling back traitor?
那个叫特纳的小伙子给了我们
The Turner boy gave us...
十个银币来救你
Ten pieces of silver to save your neck.
从这一刻起我们是盟友了
From this moment on we're to be allies.
考虑到你左手的位置
Considering where your left hand is.
- 我看我们可不只是盟友 - 我们一起去找三叉戟
- I'd say we're more than that. - We'd find the Trident together.
你能向我承诺吗
Do I have your word?
除了承诺我什么都要给你了
You're holding everything but my word.
那我把拯救我的荣誉赠予你
Then I bestow upon you the honor of saving me.
只收一点点赞助费
For a small donation.
你指望我们付钱给你来救你
You expect us to pay you to save you?
是的
Yes!
就收十个银币
For a mere 10 pieces.
疯了
Madness!
- 我们不会付超过五个 - 那行吧
- We won't pay more than 5. - Well, then.
八个就八个吧
Eight it is.
我们能不能晚点再讨论这个
Perhaps we could discuss this later.
我现在快撑不住你的左舷了
As I am having trouble here hoisting your port
- 这根本不是左舷 是我的船尾 - 你确定吗
- You are far from port, That is my stern. - Are you sure?
- 确定 - 好么 看啊
- Positive. - Well, look at this.
如果我杀了那个懦夫 女巫会吊死
If I kill the coward. The witch hangs.
- 一箭双雕 - 拜托不要放开我
- Two for the price of one. - Please don't let go of me.
他杀掉我之后可能就很难保证这一点了
It might be difficult once he kills me.
先生们 这两位囚犯将带领我们
Gentlemen, these two prisoners will lead us,
去找三叉戟
to the trident.
船长 你真觉得我们能找得到三叉戟吗
Captain. Do you really think we can find the trident?
吉布斯船长 你这是自寻烦恼
Master Gibbs, you're worrywart.
又没有什么好担心的
There is nothing to be concerned about.
- 能出什么岔子呢 - 这就是你的计划吗
- What could possibly go wrong, right? - So this was your plan?
被海盗们折磨杀害
To be tortured and killed by pirates?
你说你需要一艘船的
You said you needed a ship.
- 你管这叫船 - 切断缆索
- You call this a ship? - Cut the string!
准备出发
Prepare to drown.
我亲爱的船员们 终于
My dear beloved crew. Finally...
今天
Today is...
出问题了
Something's gone wrong.
她浮起来了
She floats!
正前方发现一只船
Ship dead ahead.
长官
Sir.
我们绝不会质疑您的决断
We would never question your reason as a captain.
但是
But, however...
您选择朝这个令人费解的方向
Is there a reason as captain, you've chosen...
航行有什么原因吗
To sail in this unreasonable direction?
告诉所有人准备迎战
Tell the men to prepare to be boarded.
坚守阵地
To stand their ground.
不要面带惧色
And show no fear.
船长 有一艘船向我们这边驶来了
Capitan! A ship sails towards us.
萨拉查船长 我听说你在寻找杰克·斯派洛
Captain Salazar. I hear you've been looking for Jack Sparrow.
原地别动
Hold point!
等候指令
And await orders.
我是巴博萨船长 我今日来此
My name is Captain Barbarossa. And I stand before you,
- 表达善意 - 我不需要什么善意
- with cordial intent. - I don't need any cordial intent.
你听到没 这个海盗想要释放善意
Do you hear that? This pirate wishes to be cordial.
我让你见识见识我的善意是什么
So let me show you what my cordiality is.
我每敲一次剑
Every time I tap my sword.
你的一名船员就会被杀掉 所以我建议你闲言少叙
One of your men will die, So I suggest you speak quickly.
船长你可能得说快点
Might want to go a bit faster Captain.
- 杰克·斯派洛在哪 - 杰克去寻找三叉戟了
- Where is Jack Sparrow? - Jack be sailing for the trident.
- 不 海洋是属于亡灵的 - 三叉戟控制着海洋
- No. The sea belongs to the dead. - The Trident controls the seas.
不 不 没有宝藏
No, no. There is no treasure.
没有宝藏
There is no treasure.
能够救得了他 他和你都会死
I can't save him. He'll die as will you.
我是唯一一位能顾带你去找他的人
I be the only one that can lead you to him.
我保证你能在明天日出前取走杰克的性命
I declare you should have Jack's life by sunrise tomorrow.
否则到时你可以取走我的 我们达成共识了吗
Or you can take me on then. Do we have an accord?
带我去找他 你就能活下来讲述这一切
Tail me to him. And you will live to tell the tale.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我代表我的船员谢谢你
I thank you on behalf of my crew.
好了 你可以带走剩下的 活人入伙了
Okay. You can take what's left them. The living come aboard.
卡丽娜 我们没多少时间了
Carina, we haven't got much time,
亡灵们正朝我们驶来
the dead are sailing straight for us.
- 是这样吗 - 是的 我和他们交谈过
- Is that so? - Yes, I've spoken to them.
你和他们交谈过
You spoken to them?
你是不是还和北海巨妖还有美人鱼说过话
Have you spoken to the Krakens and the mermaids as well?
北海巨妖不说话 是个人就知道
Krakens don't speak, everyone knows that.
当然 我就不该救你
Of course, I never should have saved you.
昨晚出现了血月 正如你描述的那样
Last night there was a blood moon, just as you described.
告诉我这揭示了什么
Tell me what to reveal.
我为什么要相信你
And why should I trust you?
你都让我托着你的走廊了 记得吗
You trusted me to hold your porch, remember?
那是我的船尾
It was my stern.
显然你还需要多在海上磨练磨练
Clearly you need to spend more time at sea.
告诉我你发现了什么我保证会帮你
Tell me what you found and I promise to help you.
我不需要帮助
I don't need any help.
卡丽娜 那你为什么还要来找我
Then why did come to me Carina?
为什么我们被绑在一起在海上
Why are we tied together in the middle of the sea...
追寻同一份宝藏
Chasing the same treasure?
月亮揭示了一条线索
The moon revealed a clue...
要释放大海的力量
To release the power of the sea.
- 必须分裂 - 分裂
- One must divide. - Divide?
- 那是什么意思 - 我还不确定
- What does it mean? - I'm not sure yet.
那么我们就去找答案
Then we'll find out.
- 这个地图集里没有地图 - 把我的日记给我
- There is no map in this map. - Give me my diary.
把无人能阅的地图给我
Give me the map no man can read.
如果你能看得着
If you could read it.
那就不会被叫做无人能阅的地图了
Then it wouldn't be call the map that no man can read.
我拜托你 别和她争
I beg you please, don't argue with her.
这艘船上大部分的人都不识字
Most of the men on this ship can't read.
使得大部分的地图
Which makes all maps.
对他们来说都是无法阅读的地图
Maps that no man can read.
如果你读不了 那么你也就不需要它和我了
Well if you can't read it, then you've no use for it, or me.
我重新说一遍 把地图给我看
Let me start again. Show me the map.
我不能 它根本不存在
I can't. It does not even exist.
- 她是个女巫 - 我是个星象家
- She's a witch! - I'm an astronomer.
- 她养驴子 - 什么 不是
- She breeds donkeys. - What? No.
- 星象家解读天象 - 是啊 在驴子上
- An astronomer contemplates the sky. - Yay, on a donkey.
- 不 没有驴子的事 - 那么你是怎么养它们的
- No, there's no donkey! - Well then how do you breed then?
让我简化一下这个交易 把地图给我
Allows me to simplify this equation. Give me the map.
不然我就杀了他 杀了他
Or I'll kill... him, or kill him.
来呀 你在虚张声势
Go on then. You're bluffing.
你脸红了
And you're blushing.
把他扔下海去
Throw him over.
我们管这叫做拖龙骨
We call this keel hauling.
小亨利会被扔下船去
Young Henry will be tossed over.
被拖在船底
And he will be dragged under the ship.
好吧
Alright.
- 你还在等什么 - 他好像没有在虚张声势
- What're you waiting for? - He doesn't appear to be bluff there.
不 我不虚张声势 他想说什么来着
No. Not bluffing me. He's trying to say something.
不 不 我们船上没有食物了 抱歉
No, no, we don't have any food on board. Sorry.
如果他走运的话 他会在
If he's lucky, he'll drown,
船底的藤壶把他切成肋排之前淹死
before the barnacles shred him to ribbon.
- 藤壶 - 像是上千把刀子
- Barnacles. - Like a thousands knives,
划过你的脊背 当然 血腥味儿会招来鲨鱼
across your back. And of course, the blood attracts sharks.
鲨鱼
Sharks?
- 船首有鲨鱼 - 在哪
- Shark of the bow! - Where?
我会说会不会游泳恐怕不是他最担心的问题了
I would say that swimming is no longer his primary concern.
地图在那
The map is there.
- 在哪 - 在你的手指尖上？
- Where? - On the tip of your finger?
不 在天上
No. In the heavens.
那本日记会把我引向
That dairy will lead me to a map,
藏在群星之间的地图
hidden in the stars.
拉他上来吧 我今晚就能找到
Let him up, I'll find it tonight.
抱歉 拉不上来了
Sorry, can't bring him up.
你自己去看
Look for yourself.
就像我说的 脸红了
As I said... Blushing!
无耻的海盗
Filthy pirate!
大海被染成血色 一名被冲上岸的水手
The sea has turned to blood, a sailor washed ashore...
在说三叉戟的事 他之前在寻找杰克·斯派洛
Talking about the Trident. He was looking for Jack Sparrow.
那个将一位女巫从绞刑架上救下的海盗
The same pirate who saved a witch from the gallows.
- 她才不是女巫 - 但你是
- She's no Witch. - But you are.
- 而你要帮助我们 - 你害怕了吗 中尉
- And you're going to help us. - You afraid, Lieutenant?
风雨欲来 你想要知道你能不能自保
As ships burning the night, you want to know if you can save your own.
- 三叉戟是否存在 - 你要为我解读那面墙
- If the trident is real? - You are going to read that wall for me.
否则你会被处死 大英帝国
Or you will die. The British Empire will have...
将会得到三叉戟并称霸海洋 我想要知道那个海盗
The trident and rule the sea. I want to know where that pirate is going,
带着那个女巫去哪了
with that witch.
你的宿命就写在群星之中 我会为你设定航向
Your destiny is in these stars. I will set your course.
不要意面墙
No Spaghetti walls.
我干嘛费那个劲来找你
Why did I bother coming to you?
亡灵在追杀我们你却在这里无所事事
The dead are haunting us down and you do nothing.
- 无所事事 你管这叫无所事事 - 你喝得醉醺醺地呼呼大睡
- Nothing, You call this nothing? - You're drunk and you're sleeping.
正是如此 我在一心二用
My point exactly, I am doing two things at once.
你没法解救不可救之人
You can't save the unsavable mate.
不管你喜欢与否 你都得帮助我
Like it or not Jack, you're going to help me.
我会打破我父亲的诅咒的
I will break my father's curse.
下次你再挥剑的时候 小伙子
Next time you raise a sword, boy.
最好别死
Be the last to die.
我建议你奉承她两句讨好她
Might I suggest you entice her with a bit of flattery.
我来这是为了我的父亲 别无他求
I am here for my father, nothing more.
我知道 早就烂熟于心了
I knew it, absolutely smitten with that.
勾搭棕发美女有一点注意事项
Now, bit of discretion when goes into brunette.
绝对不要追求她的姐妹
Never pursue her sister.
如果你实在抵不住她姐妹的魅力
But if you can not avoid the charming sister.
那就杀了哥哥 懂？
Kill the brother, savvy?
不 我不懂
No, I do not savvy.
谁伤了你 顺便说一句刚才的一点经验之谈
Who hurt you? By the way that little slim of knowledge.
- 要25个先令 - 我才不会因为那个付你钱
- Has cost you five pieces. - I am not paying you for that.
也别对女人说种句话
Never say that to a woman.
你看不到不代表就不存在
Just because you can't see something does not mean it's not there.
比如地图吗
Like the map?
我们必须找到
We have to find it.
这是弄清我和我父亲
It's the only link to who I am.
身世的唯一线索
Who my father was.
所以我们这辈子
So we both spent our lives,
都花在了找寻我们的父亲上
searching for our fathers.
也许你我要比你想象的更为相似
Perhaps you and I are closer than you think.
太阳升起来了 所以是时候了
The sun is up. And so is up time.
我无意辩驳 但是我们协议中的准确
I'm not to disagree, but the precision of our accord,
时间是太阳升起后
Ends at sunrise.
太阳才刚露头 离完全升起还早
This be will light, far from a fully rising sun.
- 我知道您是位信守诺言之人 - 诺言 你根本不了解我
- And I know you to be a man of honor. - Honor, you know nothing of me.
我知道被杰克·斯派洛打败是什么滋味
I know what it likes to be bested by Jack Sparrow.
- 他是我们共同的敌人 - 你并不知道我是谁
- He's an enemy to us both. - You don't know who I am.
我听说过一位强大的西班牙船长的故事 海上斗牛士
I've heard stories of a mighty Spanish captain. El Matador Del Mar.
一位在海上纵横捭阖 追杀了成百上千的人
A man who skirts the sea. Hunted and killed thousands of men.
不 不 不 不是人
No, no, no. Men, no, no.
不
No.
是海盗
Pirates! Eh?
海盗
Pirates.
海盗世世代代为祸海洋
Pirates had infected the seas for generations.
夺去了我父亲和祖父的性命
Taken the life of my father and his father before.
因此我发誓要一劳永逸地除掉这个祸患
So I vowed to end this plague once and for all.
我也是这么干的 我摧毁了许多海盗船
And that's what I did, I destroyed dozens of ships.
最后剩下的那些 集合起来 妄图打败我
The last ones joined together to try and defeat me.
但不久 他们也意识到 毫无希望
But they soon realized it was hopeless.
没人能阻挡沉默玛丽号
Nothing could stop the Silent Mary.
在水面以下攻击
Hit them below the water line.
快 快
Vamo, vamo!
坚持住
Hang on tight!
海洋终于 纯净了
The sea was finally... pure.
卑鄙的海盗船不会再玷污海洋
Their wretched flags will no longer stain the sea.
他们在祈求饶恕
They are begging for mercy.
怜悯？
Mercy?
绝不姑息
There's no mercy.
准备好
Make ready.
- 再见了！ - 开火！
- Adios! - Fire!
现在就看你了 杰克
It's up to you now Jack.
这个罗盘 指向你最想要的
This compass... points towards what you want most.
永远不要背叛它
Never betray it.
魔鬼三角洲
The Devil's Triangle.
他们最后的海盗船 在我眼前燃烧
The last of their ships were burning before my eyes.
就在 胜利时刻
And in that moment of... Victori.
就在那时 我听到了
It's when I heard it.
等一等 船长
Hold on, Captain.
有一条船想冲出烟雾逃跑
One ship was trying to escape through the smoke.
出海的好日子 对吧
It's a lovely day for a sail, ain't it?
就在那里
And there.
在瞭望台 就是那个年轻的海盗
In the crow's nest, there was this young pirate boy.
在我看来 就只有我们两个了
The way I see it, it just the two of us left.
你要是现在投降 我就让你活 简单极了
If you surrender to me now, I'll let you live, simple.
他站在那里 就像 一只小鸟
He stood there, looking like. A little bird...
那天之后 他赢得了那个
And from that day he earned himself a name that would...
纠缠我一辈子的名字
haunt me for the rest of my days.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack de "Sparrow".
好啦 你现在投降 我就让你活
Right, you surrender to me now, and I'll let you live.
我可以让你活下来
I shall let you live.
这个男孩
This boy.
这个男孩居然嘲笑我的力量
This boy was mocking my power.
所以我就追上去 打定主意
So I test him. Knowing that I would run...
要让我的刀已经划过他的脖子 当他死了 我就终于能...
My knife along his neck, and when he was dead, I would finish finally...
终结了所有的海盗
With pirates's life.
追上去
Follow him men!
大炮都推过来 拿一些缆绳
To the gutholes. Thread some lines.
准备急转
Prepare the boot leg!
左舷
Port side.
扔下去
Throw it now.
他们掉头了
They're turning around.
这都是什么
What's all this?
贡品 先生
Tribute... Sir.
他夺走了我的一切
He took everything from me.
让我充满 狂怒
And filled me with... rage.
和痛苦
And pain.
他就是传说的终结
And he is where the tale ends.
还没呢 船长 那里
Not yet Capitan, there.
我就说会找到的
Found as promised.
她说自己有地图
So she's saying she's got the map,
但是她是唯一能看懂的
but she's the only one who can follow it?
- 所以我们要 - 别管她
- So we should...? - Leave her be.
- 她会带我们到三叉戟 - 你都说了几个小时了
- She will take us to the Trident. - You've been saying that for hours.
我们可以确信的有两件事 白天没有星星
Two things we know are true, the stars don't shine by day.
还有 她忘了带驴子
And she forgot a donkey.
那我们怎么去一个地图上找不到的地方
How can we go to a spot, where no land exists on any map?
这个航海经线仪跟伦敦时间一模一样
This chronometer keeps the exact time in London.
我用它做海拔测量
I'm using it to make an altitude measurement...
来确定经度
To determine longitude.
只有这样 我们才能找到确切的观测点
Only then will we find our exact spot to see.
所以你是打算用一个表来找到三叉戟
So you expect to find the trident with a timepiece?
对的
Yes.
我的计算十分准确
My calculations are precise and true.
我不光是天文学家
I'm not only an Astronomer.
我也是个钟表专家
I am also a horologist.
没什么丢人的
No shame in that dear.
大家都要糊口嘛
We'll all have to earn a living, eh?
不 我说我是钟表专家
No, I'm a horologist.
我妈也是啊 她也没有像你这样大声宣布
So was my mum. But she didn't cry a bad as lad as you.
你的意思是你妈也有一定学术研究背景吗
You saying your mother was academically inclined?
不如说 平躺着的背景吧
More like a horizontally, reclined.
钟表学是研究时间的
Horology is the study of time.
她也总在看时间啊
And she was always looking at watch.
这点我敢保证
I can vouch for that.
所以 只有你能找到宝藏 是么
So no one can find the X, but you, right?
不
No.
- 还有驴子吗 - 后方有船
- And the donkey? - Ship to the f!
萨拉查
Salazar.
杰克 亡灵在得到复仇之前是不会停下的
Jack, the dead will not rest until they get their revenge.
亡灵
Dead?
不 不 亡灵
No, no, the dead.
- 你没说有亡灵的事情 - 就不应该来
- Were never part of this deal. - We should've never follow.
跟着一个倒霉船长和女巫出海
A luck less pirate and a witch to sea.
不管了 把他们都杀了
Right, that's it. Kill them all.
杀了我 然后 然后我就死了
Kill me and, and... I will be dead.
那些亡灵就没法复仇了
And then the other dead won't be able to have the revenge.
对我复仇
Against me,
- 我就死了 - 什么
- I'd be dead. - What?
- 他们将会更加愤怒 - 他说得对
- Which will anger them even more. - He's right.
说得对
That's right.
海盗都这么没脑子么
Are all pirates this stupid?
对的
Yes.
那我们怎么办呢
What are we going to do?
作为船长
As Captain.
我能建议下么
Might I suggest.
兵变 你非得建议兵变
Mutiny? You had to suggest a mutiny?
卡丽娜 亡灵就要来了
Carina, the dead are coming.
反正 我是不相信什么超自然的屁话
Well. I choose not to believe in supernatural nonsense.
你难道没看到我们身后是什么
Do you not see what's behind us?
- 把它们放下去 - 遵命
- Drop them! - Si.
放下去
Drop them!
你干什么
What are you doing?
船上的那些人在找杰克
Men on that ship are looking for Jack.
杰克在这条小船上
And Jack is on this boat.
我还是逃跑吧
I'm going to swim for it.
你怎么敢学我
How dare you do exactly what I'd do if I were you?
- 卡丽娜 别这样 - 不 不 不 千万别停
- Carina stop! - No, no, no, don't stop.
- 你够了 - 够什么够
- This has gone far enough. - No, it has not.
别听他的 接着脱 接着脱！
Listen not to him, carry on, carry on!
- 干嘛 眼看着要脱光了 - 我看到她的脚踝了
- Why, she was almost finished. - I saw her ankles.
你个傻小子要是闭嘴还能看到更多呢
You'd have to seen a lot more, if you kept the cakeholes shut.
去杀了斯派洛
Kill the sparrow.
这可不妙
That's not good, is it?
接着划 伙计 再快点！
Keep rowing man. Faster!
不 受够鸟
No, that's it.
我去找她了
I'm going with her.
你为了个光穿内衣的钟表专家就要抛弃我？
You would leave me for some horologist in her knickers?
没错
Yes.
臭男人都一个样
You men are all alike.
鲨鱼
Shark.
亨利！
Henry!
看来没用
Doesn't seem to be working.
不 没事儿 没事儿的
No, we'll be fine, we'll be fine.
- 这是怎么搞的 - 我们必须游泳了
- How did they do that? - We have to swim.
我来引开他
I will distract him.
就现在
Now!
亨利
Henry!
嗨 杰克·斯派洛
Hi... Jack Sparrow.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow.
西班牙人
Spanish?
鬼魂
Ghosts.
他们无法登陆
They are unable to step on land.
- 我就知道 - 有鬼啊！
- I knew that. - Ghosts!
- 卡丽娜 - 你很快就会为自己所做的付出代价
- Carina! - You will soon pay for what you did to me.
不 不 不 真心不用麻烦了
No no no. There is no need to bother really.
- 卡丽娜 - 没空跟你聊
- Carina! - I have no time to chat.
- 因为我的地图要跑了 - 那我等着你
- Because mi map just ran away. - I'll be waiting for you.
等我干嘛 他为什么非要等我
Why would you be waiting for me? Why would he be waiting for me?
有海盗
Pirates!
史考姆
Scrum.
船长
Captain?
杰克说 如果他有什么意外
Jack always told me that if anything should ever happened to him.
- 他要你当船长 - 但是大家支持你
- He wanted you to be captain. - Yes, but the men voted for you, yes?
所以 你得到了船长的帽子
Well, you've got a captain's hat!
尽管如此 那是杰克的遗愿呢
"Be that as it may" them were his wishes.
所以听话 去掌舵吧
So be a good lad and take the wheel.
还有你
And... you,
- 帽子归你了 - 哎呀妈呀 好荣幸
- Take the captain's hat. - Perish my rhythm.
我们要揍死你们的船长
We will beat your captain to death.
除非他告诉我们他们去哪里了
Until he reveals where they are heading.
- 卡丽娜 - 我知道你纠结的是什么
- Carina! - I know what's ailing you boy.
你有个地方痒痒但是挠不到
You've got the unstretchable itch.
卡丽娜是唯一能带我们找到三叉戟的人
Carina is the only one who can help us find the Trident.
- 我才没有爱上她 - 爱？
- And I'm not in love with her. - Love?
谁说你爱了 你说什么呢？
Who said anything about love, what are you talking about?
挠不到的痒痒
The unstretchable itch.
疥疮 我说的是疥疮
Scabies, I'm talking about scabies.
皮肤下面的钻来钻去小虫子
Small mites that burrow under the skin.
烦死我了 都好几年了
Certainly annoying me, has done for years.
糟糕
Oh, no!
救命
Help!
- 救救我 救命 - 卡丽娜
- Help me! Help! - Carina!
- 亨利 帮帮我 - 快帮她
- Henry, help me. - Help her!
奉天承运 国王诏曰
By rule of the King.
你们全被判处死刑
I sentence you all to death.
我们应该透露下彼此的私房钱藏哪里了
I think we should tell each other where our treasures are buried...
万一谁幸存了可以交给他
Just in case one of us survives.
好主意
Oh, good idea.
- 你先说 - 我的宝藏被埋在
- You go first. - My treasure is buried...
阿鲁巴岛上两颗交叉的棕榈树下为标记的墓地
Between two cross palm trees in an unmarked grave in Aruba.
你的宝藏呢
What about yours?
我没有宝藏
I haven't got any.
你答应我杀死杰克的
You promised me Jack's blood.
但杰克被困住了
But Jack is trapped!
- 他永远逃不出去了 - 再小也是陆地！
- He can never escape the island. - Piece of land!
你们好
Hello.
我遵守了约定
I upheld our deal.
我和手下会上岸去
Mi men and myself will go ashore.
我会把叛徒交还给你
The traitor will be yours.
- 以我的名誉发誓 - 名誉
- On mi honor. - Honor?
你这个家伙有何名誉可言
What honor, hombre? What honor?
- 你根本不懂名誉 - 请绕我一命
- You don't know what the honor is. - Spare mi my life.
我会把你要的小矮子斯派洛带来
And I'll fetch you little Sparrow.
同意吗
An accord?
醒醒 斯派洛
Wake up Sparrow.
Wake up, Sparrow.
- 是时候还债了 - 猪哥
- It's time to pay your debt. - Pig?
凯莉猪
Pig Kelly?
- 我的老伙计 - 伙计
- Mi old mate. - Mate?
孩子们听到没
Do you hear that boys?
这个海盗欠我一大笔银子
This pirate owes me a blunder of silver.
老天爷将他带到了刽子湾
And luck has brought him to Hangman's Bay.
在这他能还清欠款 从此两清
Where he can settle his debt, here and now.
我会的 猪哥 你说个数吧
And I will, I will Pig. Name your price.
她叫碧翠丝
Her name is Beatrice.
她是我可怜的寡妇妹妹
And she is my poor widowed sister.
啊 那是什么玩意啊
What, what is that?
她一直在找好男人
She's been looking for a respectable man.
- 但你也勉强可以了 - 罗伊斯 赶紧开始吧
- But you'll have to do. - Royce, let's get on with this.
不 为什么 为什么非？...
No why? Why?...
让她做回女人 对她好 杰克
To make an honest woman of her, Jack.
恭喜你 今天你要结婚了
Congratulations, it's your wedding day.
可以开始了吗
Let us begin?
我们会在谷仓中度蜜月
We will honeymoon in the barn.
不 别这样 猪哥
No, no, no. Pig.
我怎么可能真心实意地对它好呢
How can I honestly make an honest woman out of it?
她 我的意思是她
That, her. I mean. Her.
- 这玩意都是什么 - 我们的子嗣
- What are those things? - Our children.
最好别和他们对视
Best not look them in the eye.
带伴娘伴郎来
Bring the best man and the bridesmaid.
我看它的眼睛了
I looked it in the eye.
将手放在圣经上
Place your hand on the Bible.
- 我有疥疮 - 巧了 我也有
- I have got scabies. - So do I.
手放在圣经上
Place your hand on the Bible.
我爱尿炕
I'm a bed wetter.
说你愿意
Say I do.
- 否则我爆了你的头 - 杰克 他们真要杀死我们
- Or I'll put a bullet in your skull. - Jack, they are going to kill us.
- 我不在乎 - 快同意吧
- I don't care! - Just say I do.
- 最后机会 - 等下 当然
- Last chance Jack. - Wait. Surely...
- 这并不合法 - 不合法
- This is not legal. - This is not legal.
他说得对
He's right.
在场有人反对这桩婚姻吗？
Does any man here object to the nuptials?
- 我 - 恭喜
- I do. - Congratulations.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
你爱吃海鲜 对吧？
Do you like seafood, do you?
杰克 又见面了
Jack. We meet again.
赫克托
Hector!
这是我全世界最好的朋友
This is mi best mate in the whole world.
我一直知道你早晚会安心结婚
I always knew you'll settle down, eventually.
你给我带礼物了吗
Did you bring me a gift?
这样也行
That'll do.
你看着很精神 脚步十分轻盈
You look marvelous. Got quite a spring in your step.
你的腿长出来了吗
Has your leg grown back?
船长 我们不该回去找萨拉查
Captain, shouldn't we be getting back to Salazar.
用斯派洛先生的命换我们的吗？
Trade Mr. Sparrow's life in for our own?
可以那么做 但我是来找波塞冬三叉戟的
I know that we could. But I've come for the Trident Poseidon.
你要出卖那帮亡灵吗？
You're gonna double cross the dead?
你向他们承诺过
You did promise!
所以我会摧毁偷走我对大海控制权的亡灵
And with it I'll gut the dead that stole my command of the sea.
虽然我很喜欢这个计划
As much as I love this plan.
什么船都逃不脱那凄惨可悲的船的魔掌
No vessel can outrun that wretched haul of the ship.
有的 杰克
But there be one, Jack.
我见过的最快的船
The fastest ship I know.
黑珍珠号 被困在黑胡子的瓶子里
The pearl, trapped in that bottle by Blackbeard.
五个寒冬前
Five winters ago.
以强盗至高无上的剑起誓
By the power of that blaggerd sovereign blade...
我在此返还黑珍珠号曾经应得的荣耀
I hereby release the Black Pearl, to her former and rightful glory.
弄掉那
Get rid of the...
要来了
It's coming.
它要出现了 来了来了
It is coming! It is coming! Coming!
放一边
Set aside.
要来了
It's coming!
缩水了
It's shrunken.
为什么不能恢复原样呢
Why doesn't it unshrink?
也许天太冷了
Maybe it's cold.
她要回到海上
She needs the sea.
她曾经是艘好船
She was a fine ship.
船上只需要一位船长
There be room for only one captain.
- 肮脏的畜生 - 该去与亡灵赛跑了
- Filthy beast. - Time to race the dead.
唯一安全的地方就是陆地
The only safe place is the land.
为什么我们要离开陆地
Why are we going away from the land?
没人知道吗
Nobody knows?
船长 你的地图不完整
Captain, your map is incomplete.
如果你相信我 我能带大家去找三叉戟
I can take us to the Trident, if you'd only trust me.
你听我刚才说的了吗
Did you not hear anything I just said?
所以你的意思是
So you be saying.
那颗星星假装自己是地图吗
Is that star pretending to be a map?
船长 任何地图上都没有陆地
Sir, there is no island, on any map,
那女人说的毫无根据
to support what the woman says.
船长 你不用理解她说的话
Captain, you don't have to understand her.
只需要相信她
Just believe her.
有人吗？
Any one?
要是有锋利的东西 我就能撬锁
We had something sharp, I could pick that lock.
在这里你绝对找不到锋利的玩意
You are not gonna find anything sharp in here.
放了他们
Release them.
船长 你不会想让女人掌舵吧
Sir, you wouldn't allow a woman to steer your ship?
让她去追星星 否则我们都会死
She will follow her star. Or we'll all die together.
黑珍珠号 又起航了
The Black Pearl. She sails again.
这艘船 那些鬼
This ship. Those ghosts.
都无法用常理来解释
There can be no logical explanation.
海之传说是真的 卡丽娜
Myths of the sea are real, Carina.
很高兴你终于能意识到自己想错了
I'm glad you can finally see you were wrong.
错
Wrong?
也许我确实怀疑过
Perhaps I had some doubts.
这是我听过最糟的道歉了
This is the worst apology I've ever heard.
道歉 我为什么要道歉
Apology? Why would I apologize?
因为我们在被亡灵追捕 开一艘
Because we've been chased by the dead, sailing on a ship,
从瓶子里蹦出的船 科学如何解释
raised from a bottle. Where is your science in that?
好吧 我会道歉
Fine, I will apologize.
接着说
Go on, then.
那样的话 你可能也要和我道歉
Well then, one could argue that you owe me an apology.
我的生命因为你被海盗与亡灵威胁
As my life has been threatened by pirates and dead man.
现在你相信了 虽然这么说很欠打
Which you now believe in, sorry to say.
我原谅你
Apology accepted.
我去望风
I am going to the lookout.
很高兴你这么想
I'm glad you see it my way!
- 准备好枪 - 准备好枪
- Ready the guns. - Aye. Ready the guns!
这些海盗是冲着三叉戟来的
These pirates are going for the trident.
这你是从哪拿到的 姑娘
Where did you get that from Missy?
我知道这本书 十多年前
I know this book, stolen from an Italian ship,
- 从意大利船上偷的 - 偷
- many years ago. - Stolen?
不 你看认错了
No, you're mistaken.
书封皮上本有一颗红宝石
There was a Ruby on the cover...
非常记忆犹新
I would not soon forget.
这是我父亲给我的
This was given to me by my father.
他明明是个科学家
He was clearly a man of science.
显然他是个小偷
He was clearly a common thief.
我对父亲的回忆
The memory of my father will not be befouled...
才不会被海盗之舌玷污
by the tongue of a pirate.
这本日记是我生来就有的
This diary is my birth right.
被放在儿童之家的台阶上
Left to me on the steps of a children's home.
还留了一个名字 仅此而已
Along with a name and nothing else.
所以你是孤儿咯
Oh, so you are an orphan?
你叫什么
What be you called?
北方的明亮之星赋予我名字
Brightest star in the North gave me my name.
- 所以你叫卡丽娜 - 卡丽娜·史密斯
- That would be Carina? - Carina Smyth.
- 你确实很了解星象 - 我是船长
- So, you do know your stars? - I'm a captain.
我知道跟着哪颗星星能回家
I know which stars to follow home.
史密斯
Smyth?
史密斯十个不同寻常的姓
Smyth is quite an unusual name.
我们不也认识一位吗 老史密斯
Did we not once know someone, old Smyth?
别捣乱
Shut your trip.
她叫什么来着
What was her name.
到嘴边了就是想不出
It's right on the tip of mi tongue...
你想丢掉舌头吗
Do you wanna loose that tongue?
玛格丽特·史密斯
Margaret Smyth.
我们达成一致了吗
Aye, so we making accord then?
还是我去告诉那个人
Or, Shall I tell you know who...
我们都知道真相
What we both know it's the truth.
你我要把这个秘密带入坟墓
We both take the secret to our grave.
所以是真的咯 我只是在虚张声势
You mean, it is true? I was bluffing.
才不是
I am not!
杀了我 你就没东西给亡灵了
You kill me, you got nothing to bow to the deadness.
你需要我
So you need me.
必须坦白 赫克托 你真的非常非常丑
I will have to frank Hector. You are very, very ugly.
你怎么会生出那么位可人呢？
So how could you produce a fetching creature such as that?
玛格丽特死了
Margaret died.
我尽了一个不成器的强盗最大的努力
That worthless blaggerd ever could.
我把还是婴儿的她送进孤儿院 不曾回去看她
I placed the infant in an orphanage, never to see her again.
我以为留下红宝石可以让她过得好一点
I thought the ruby might afford her some easy life...
没想到她会去研究那本日记
But I never imagined she would take those scribblings...
想要解开身世之谜
Make a life of her own.
还是回到了我身边
Life that's led her back to me.
看来现在情况对我非常有利 老爹
I would say this puts me in a rather favorable position, Daddy.
- 要什么你说 - 我要我的罗盘
- Tell me what you want. - I want mi compass.
还有216桶的兰姆酒和这只猴子
216 barrels of rum. And a monkey.
- 你想养杰克 - 晚餐
- You want Jack? - Dinner.
我要把它当晚餐吃掉
I want to eat him. I want to eat that monkey.
不行杰克 这么聪明的姑娘
No deal Jack. A clever young woman such as that,
是绝对不会相信我这样的人会是她的父亲
would never believe that a swine like me could ever be her blood.
而且我一定要得到三叉戟
And the Tridente will be mine.
皇家海军
Redcoats.
皇家海军来了
Redcoats!
准备射击
Prepare to fire!
Prepare to fire.
敌军从右弦那边摸过来了
She comes starboard.
我们要奋战到底
We shall fight to the last.
黑珍珠号绝不能再次被夺走
The pearl will not be taken from me again...
长官
Sir.
海上的控制权只能属于大英帝国
Only the British Empire will hold the power of the sea.
不论发生什么事 只管保持航线
What ever happens, stay your course.
杰克·斯派洛
Jack Sparrow?
我来找你算账了
I've come with the butcher's bill.
他人呢
Where is he?
大家准备战斗 跟他们拼了
Defend yourselves men! Till again!
能不能快点 你这刀子是用黄油磨出来的吗
Hurry up man, what did you... sharpen it with butter?
看你往哪儿躲
There is nowhere to hide.
勇敢起来 让我们为黑珍珠号而战
Let's be brave, save the Pearl.
就是这里
This has to be it.
- 应该在这里 - 往那片陆地上开
- It has to be here. - Sail that land.
我的天
Oh mi Lord's eye.
快到了
We're nearly there.
应该就在附近
It's here somewhere.
找到那地方了吗 小姐
Have you found what you were looking for yet, miss?
我正在找
I'm trying!
星星就要看不见了
The stars will soon be gone.
卡丽娜
Carina!
亨利 你看 小岛就在那里
Henry! Look, the island is there.
你找到了
You found it!
那座岛
The island.
陆地
Land!
快去
Get to the...
卡丽娜
Carina!
亨利
Henry!
他们抓走了亨利
They took Henry!
现在只有三叉戟才能救他
The trident be all that can save him now.
那么我们一定要找到三叉戟
Then we have to find it.
三叉戟在哪里
Where is it?
一定在这里
It has to be here.
快来看 杰克
Look at it Jack.
我从没见过这么漂亮的东西
It's most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
这是父亲希望我找到的
This is what my father wanted to find.
石头吗
The rocks?
不不是石头 是星星
No, no. Not rocks, stars.
它就是无人能懂的海图指引的地方
This is the map no man can read.
整座岛是天堂的完美倒影
This island is a perfect reflection of the heavens.
少了一颗星星 快来
One star's missing, quickly.
我们必须找三叉戟才能救亨利
We have to find the trident to save Henry.
赫克托
Hector.
你应该知道她是个钟表专家
I think you should know she's a horologist.
它为什么不在闪烁
Why is not it glowing?
把它放回原位 卡丽娜
Finish it, Carina.
丢失的那一角
The missing star.
为了我的父亲
For my father.
没错
Aye...
为了他
Do it for him.
看
There.
- 波塞冬之墓 - 这边
- Posiedon's tomb. - This way.
船长
Capitan.
你知道这很危险的 别那么做
You know the danger. Don't do it!
没别的办法了 杰克已经上岸去找三叉戟了
We have no choice. Jack is on land going for the trident.
船长 一定有别的办法的
Capitan, there must be another way.
一旦你附身活人
Once you possess the living,
就再也回不来了 你会困在他身体里面
there is no coming back. You will be trapped in his body.
直到永远
Forever.
三叉戟能还我自由的
The Tridente will set me free.
- 是时候去杀斯派洛了 - 不
- Time to kill a sparrow. - No!
- 快看 杰克 就在那 - 三叉戟
- Look Jack, there it is. - The trident.
杰克！
Jack!
你伤了我就等于伤了亨利
You cut me, you cut the boy Jack.
- 亨利！- 不
- Henry! - No.
又见面啦 斯派洛
Hola, Sparrow.
不
No.
斯派洛 斯派洛
Sparrow, Sparrow.
不
No.
亨利 把他唤醒拜托
Henry, you've woken him up Please.
亨利快醒醒
Henry wake up!
滚开
Oh, piss off!
亨利快醒醒 他要杀杰克
Henry wakes up, he is killing Jack.
亨利
Henry!
- 大海之力 - 什么
- Power of the sea. - What?
- 大海之力 - 要释放大海之力
- The power of the sea. - To release the power of the sea...
必须分离
All must divide.
如果三叉戟掌握着所有的力量 那么
If the trident holds all the power, then.
那么所有的诅咒都会存在其中
Then every curse is held inside.
就像我之前告诉你的那样
As I told you before.
现在向我投降 我就不会
Surrender to me now. And I will let you.
- 杀你 - 你想让我投降？
- Live. - Do you want me to surrender?
- 也许 - 审判到此结束
- Maybe. - This is where the trail ends.
不要
No!
分离
Divide.
亨利
Henry!
分离
Divide.
破坏
Break.
打破三叉戟就能破坏大海的诅咒
Break the trident and you'll break off the curses of the sea.
拜拜了 斯派洛
Adios, Sparrow.
所有的诅咒都消除了
All curses have broken.
太好了
Yes!
- 黑珍珠号 我的黑珍珠号 - 快爬
- The Pearl! My Pearl! - Climb.
快走
Move, fast!
开稳了伙计们 别让它滑下去
Hold it steady boys, don't let it slip.
杰克！
Jack!
快点！
Faster!
起锚
Lift, anchor!
快起锚
Get the anchor up, quick!
停下停下 起锚
Stop, stop, bring it up.
快起锚
Bring it up!
船长
Capitan!
该死
Oh, crap!
我抓住你了
I've got ya.
我对你来说是什么？
Who am I to you?
宝藏
Treasure.
抓住了
Hold on!
赫克托
Hector!
去右舷
Go to starboard!
这是海盗的宿命 赫克托
Pirate's life, Hector.
你还好吧？
You were right?
说不清
I don't know.
有一瞬间我像是拥有了一切，亨利
For a moment I had everything, Henry.
但现在又全没了
Now it's all gone again.
没有全都失去 史密斯小姐
It's not all gone, Miss. Smyth.
巴博萨 我姓巴博萨
Barbarossa... My name is Barbarossa.
- 也许杰克说的没错 - 说什么
- Maybe Jack was right. - About what?
你是难挠之痒
You unstretchable itch.
你为什么打我
Why did you do that for?
看看是不是真的你
Just checking it's truly you.
我怕你又被附身
That you are not still cursed.
- 是真的我 - 那是我
- It's me. - Then I was...
- 错了 - 小失误
- Wrong. - Slightly an error.
不过
Although one.
我原谅你了
Apology accepted.
是荷兰人号
The Dutchman.
- 亨利？- 是我 老爸
- Henry? - Yes father.
看看你 长这么大了
Oh, look at you son.
你怎么做到的？
How did you do it?
- 你怎么打破诅咒的？- 让我给你讲个故事
- How did you break the curse? - Let me tell you a tale.
人类史上最伟大宝藏的故事
The tale of the greatest treasure known to man.
我很想听听
That's the tale I wanna hear.
肉肉麻麻的城里人
What a silly revolting sight.
让一让
Make way!
杰克·斯派洛船长本人
Captain Jack Sparrow on deck...
驾到了
Indeed.
欢迎回来 船长
Welcome back, Captain.
我非常感谢你 让一让
I thank you very much, coming through.
- 船长 - 谢谢你 我记得你
- Captain! - Thank you, I remember you.
- 谢谢你 - 我的天
- Cheers, thank you. - Oh good!
吉布斯总管
Master Gibbs.
船由你掌舵了船长
The ship is yours Captain.
谢谢你
Aye, thank you!
猴子
Monkey.
谢谢你...
Thank you...
我们下一步要去哪
What be aye heading captain?
我们要追逐星辰
We should follow the stars,
吉布斯总管
Master Gibbs.
说的极是 船长！
Aye... aye, Captain!
我有个约会... 在亲爱的地平线彼端...
I have a rendezvous beyond my... Beloved horizon.